Granville Hicks Papers
Granville Hicks Papers
- Printed material
  - Pamphlets
    - Political economy in the Soviet Union. New York, International Publishers, 1944 (Box 113)
    - Political education: Part 1, the two worlds. New York, International Publishers, 1935 (Box 113)
    - Poll tax facts. New York, Workers Defense League, undated (Box 113)
    - The Present situation and the next tasks. New York, New Century Publishers, 1945; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - A Primer of economics. New York, Social Action and Association Press, undated; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Radek, Karl. Proletarian dictatorship and terrorism. Detroit, Marxian Educational Society, undated; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Roy, Manabendra Nath. I Accuse! New York, Roy Defense Committee of India, 1932 (Box 113A)
    - Shipkov, Michael. Breakdown. New York, National Committee for Free Europe, Inc., 1950?; with promotional sheet for the National Committee for Free Europe, Inc.; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Silverman, Harriet. The People's health. New York People's National Health Committee, 1938; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Sinclair, Upton. What can be done about America's economic troubles? New York, Pasadena, Upton Sinclair, 1939; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Sinclair, Upton and Eugene Lyons. Terror in Russia? New York, Rand School Press, 1938 (Box 113A)
    - Smirnov, A.A. Shakespeare: a Marxist interpretation. New York, Critics' Group, 1936; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Sprenger, Rudolf. Bolshevism. New York, International Review, undated (Box 113A)
    - Stalin, Joseph. Foundations of Leninism. New York, International Publishers, 1934; 10th anniversary edition (Box 113)
    - Stalin, Joseph. The Lenin heritage. New York, International Publishers, 1934; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Stalin, Joseph. Stalin's Speeches on the American Communist Party. New York, Workers Library Publishers, 6 May 1929; 14 May 1929 (Box 113)
    - Steinbeck, John. "Their blood is strong." San Francisco, Simon J. Lubin Society of California, Inc., 1938; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Stevens, Bennett. The Church and the Workers. New York, Union Labor, 1932 (Box 113)
    - The Supreme Court on the Bridges case New York, American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, 1945; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Symes, Lillian. Communism - World Revolution to Red Imperialism. Chicago, undated (Box 113)
    - Thompson, Robert. The Path of a renegade: why Earl Browder was expelled from the Communist Party. New York, New Century Publishers, 1946 (Box 113)
    - Thorez, Maurice. Catholics and Communists. New York, Workers Library Publishers, Oct 1938 (Box 113)
    - Toward an American Revolutionary Labor Movement. New York, Provisional Organizing Committee of the American Workers Party, 1934 (Box 113A)
    - Trachtenberg, Alexander. The History of May Day. New York, International Pamphlets, 1932 (Box 113)
    - Trotsky, Leon. The Kirov Assassination. New York, Workers Library Publishers, 30 Dec 1934; Feb 1935 (Box 113)
    - Trumbo, Dalton. The Time of the toad: a study of inquisition in America by one of the Hollywood Ten. Hollywood, Hollywood Ten, undated; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Two speeches by Karl Marx: Address to the Communist League, 1850; and The Inaugural address of the International Workingmen's Association. Vancouver, Historical Research Bureau, undated; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Wells, H.G. Marxism vs. liberalism: an interview (with Joseph Stalin). Introduction by Granville Hicks. New York, International Publishers, 1935; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Wilgus, Asa. The Size of our family. New York, Profile Press, 1948; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Wolfe, Bertram D.. What is the Communist Opposition. New York, Workers Age Publishing Association, 1933 (Box 113)
    - Yergan, Max and Robeson, Paul. The Negro and justice: a plea for Earl Browder. New York, Citizens' Committee to Free Earl Browder, 1941 (Box 113)
    - Yvon, M.. What has become of the Russian Revolution. New York, International Review, 1937 (Box 113)
  - Periodicals
    - The Adelphi, volume 5, no. 6 through volume 6 no. 2, Mar-May 1933; 3 issues (Box 113)
    - The Christian Leader, vol. 39, no. 5, Feb. 1936 (Box 113)
    - The Christian Century, vol. 54, no. 13, Mar. 1937 (Box 113)
    - Communist Review, vol. 5, no. 3-4, Mar. - Apr. 1933 (Box 113)
    - Debate, vol. 1, no. 2, Mar. 1934; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Dialectics, numbers 1, 6, and 9, 1937-1938; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging; please refer to
    - Dialogue, vol. 1, no. 1, 1968 (Box 114)
    - Educational Trends, vol. 5, no. 1, Dec. 1936 (Box 114)
    - Good Morning, vol. 3, no. 1, Jan. 1, 1921; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging; please refer to
    - The Harvard Monthly, volume 65, numbers 1, 3, Mar. 1937; June 1937 (Box 114)
    - Hound and Horn, vol. 6, no. 1, Oct./Dec. 1932 (Box 114)
    - International Literature, 1932-1939; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The Interpreter, vol. 2, no. 20; vol. 3, no. 1-2, 7, 1946-1947 (Box 114)
    - The Labour Monthly, vol. 15, no. 3-4; vol. 28, no. 9, Mar. - Apr. 1933; Sept. 1946 (Box 114)
    - Left Front, vol. 1, no. 2, vol. 1, no. 3-4, 1933-1934; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The Left News, no. 11, Mar. 1937; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Left Review, vol. 1, no. 3, vol. 3, no. 13, Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The Literary Workshop, vol. 1, no. 2 and 3, 1934; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Literature of the World Revolution, numbers 1, 4 and 5 as well as Special Issue, 1931; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Literature of the World Revolution, number 2, 1931; in German (Box 114)
    - The Magazine: a Literary Review, vol. 1, no. 1, Dec. 1933; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Midwest: a Review, vol. 1, no. 3, 1937; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Modern Socialism, Fall, 1941; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The Monthly Review, vol. 1, no. 1, 1934; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Mundus Artium, vol. 1, no. 1-2, 1967-1968 (Box 115)
    - New Frontier, vol. 1, no. 2, 1936; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The New Leader, vol. 33, no. 18 - no. 51, May 6, 1950 - Dec. 25, 1950; 4 folders (Box 115)
    - The New Leader, vol. 34, no. 1 - vol. 35, no. 8, Jan. 1, 1951 - Feb. 25, 1952; 7 folders (Box 116)
    - The New Leader, vol. 35, no. 9 - vol. 36, no. 17, Mar. 3, 1952 - Apr. 27, 1953; 7 folders (Box 117)
    - The New Leader, vol. 36, no. 18 - vol. 37, no. 39, May 4, 1953 - Dec. 27, 1954; lacks May 30, 1954 - Aug. 30, 1954; 8 folders (Box 118)
    - The New Leader, vol. 38, no. 1 - vol. 39, no. 18, Jan. 3, 1955 - Apr. 30, 1956; lacks July 3, Aug. 29, 1955; 7 folders (Box 119)
    - The New Leader, vol. 39, no. 19 - vol. 40, no. 25, May 7, 1956 - Jun, 24, 1957; 7 folders (Box 120)
    - The New Leader, vol. 40, no. 26 - vol. 43, no. 26, Jul. 1, 1957 - Jun. 27, 1960; lacks Aug. - Dec. 1957 and all of 1958 until Dec. 15, and July 13, 1959; 7 folders (Box 121)
    - The New Leader, vol. 43, no. 27/28- vol. 45, no. 13, Jul. 4, 1960 - June 25, 1962; lacks Sept. 26, 1960, Mar. 6, 1961; 7 folders (Box 122)
    - The New Quarterly, vol. 1, no. 1-2, 1934; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - New Theatre, Feb. 1934 - Apr. 1936; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - New Times, Sept. 15 - Oct. 1, 1945; Jan. 15 - Feb. 1, 1946;; Aug. 15, 1946; 2 folders (Box 123)
    - Nieman Reports, vol. 1, no. 1, Feb. 1947 (Box 123)
    - Partisan Review, 1934-1938; 11 items; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Playboy, "The Decent Society", Jan. 1969 (Box 123)
    - The Plebs, vol. 25, no. 3-4, Mar. - Apr. 1933; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Political Affairs, vol. 24, no. 11 and vol. 25, no. 3, Nov. 1945; Mar. 1946; 2 items (Box 123)
    - The Quest, vol. 1, no. 1, 1965-1966 (Box 123)
    - Science and Society: a Marxian Quarterly, vol. 1, no. 4, 1937; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The Social Frontier, vol. 1, no's 3 and 7; vol. 2, no. 6, Dec. 1934; Apr. 1935,; Mar. 1936; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Spark March issue, vol. 1, no. 1, Mar 1937 (Box 123)
    - Story, no. 4-11, 1931-1933; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Le Surrealisme au Service de la Revolution, no. 3, 4, 1931; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The Symposium, vol. 3, no's 1-4; vol. 3, no. 3-4; vol. 4, no. 2, 1932; 1933; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Transition, numbers 3, 6 and 8, June 1927; Sept. 1927,; Nov. 1927 (Box 123)
    - Transition, number 19/20, June 1930 (Box 124)
    - Vanguard, vol. 4, no. 1, Nov. 1937; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - The Windsor Quarterly, vol. 2, no. 3-4, 1935; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
  - Philomath, Framingham High School Graduation number (Box 109)
  - Reach, James. The Darktown Jamboree (Box 109)
  - Saturday Review, Chronology of popular music for authors 1908-1941, Jan. 30, 1943 (Box 109)
  - "The Second Battle of Concord" (Box 109)
  - Siena College Greyfriar Series program, 1966-1967 (Box 109)
  - Skidmore College Founder's Week Program, April 21 - 28, 1968 (Box 109)
  - "Some Speed" (play by Hicks) program, 1922 (Box 109)
  - "Walled in This Tomb", See Correspondence: subject files: Harvard-Sacco-Vanzetti Committee.
  - War ration book (Box 109)
  - Young People's Christian Union. Program of the Thirty-first Annual Convocation, 1920 (Box 109)
  - The Young Writer at Chapel Hill, 1968 (Box 109)
  - Miscellany (Box 109)
- Unrevised galleys, proofs and review copies
  - Authors Guild, Inc. The Writer's world, edited by Elizabeth Janeway. New York, McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1969 (Box 125)
  - Becker, Stephen D. A Covenant with death. New York, Atheneum, 1964 [i.e. 1965] (advance copy) (Box 125)
  - Bell, Charles G. The Half gods. Boston, Houghton Mifflin Company, 1968 (Box 125)
  - Betts, Doris. The Scarlet thread. New York, Harper and Row, 1964 (Box 125)
  - Dohrman, Richard. Vonda Rosegood. New York, Harper and Row, 1965; 2 folders (Box 126)
  - Foster, Malcolm. Joyce Cary: a biography. Boston, Houghton Mifflin, 1968 (Box 126)
  - Hicks, Granville. Literary horizons: a quarter century of American fiction. New York, New York University Press, 1970 (Box 127)
  - Hicks, Granville. Part of the truth: an autobiography. New York, Harcourt, Brace and World, 1965; 3 copies (Box 127)
  - Horgan, Paul. Everything to live for. New York, Farrar, Straus and Giroux, Inc., 1968 (Box 127)
  - Johnson, Josephine W. The Inland island. New York, Simon and Schuster, 1969 (Box 126)
  - La Farge, Oliver. The Door in the wall. Boston, Houghton Mifflin Co., 1965 (Box 126)
  - Laxalt, Robert. A Man in the wheatfield. New York, Harper and Row, 1964 (Box 126)
  - Leigh, James. What can you do? New York, Harper and Row, 1965 (Box 128)
  - McKinley, Georgia. Follow the running grass. Boston, Houghton Mifflin Co., 1969 (Box 128)
  - Mamis, Justin. Love. New York, Stein and Day, 1964 (Box 128)
  - North, Sterling. The Wolfling. New York, E.P. Dutton and Co., 1969 (Box 128)
  - North, Sterling. The Wolfling., documentary notes by the author (Box 128)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol. Them. New York, Vanguard Press, 1969 (Box 128)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol. With shuddering fall. New York, Vanguard Press, 1964 (Box 128)
  - O'Connor, Frank. A Set of variations. New York, Alfred A. Knopf, 1969 (Box 129)
  - Owen, Guy. The Ballad of the flim-flam man. New York, Macmillan, 1965; separately annotated (Box 129)
  - Rosskam, Edwin. The Alien. New York, Grossman Publishers, 1964 (Box 129)
  - Scott, Paul. The Corrida at San Feliu. New York, William Morrow, 1964 (Box 131)
  - Seitlin, Percy. Is anything all right? New York, Grossman Publishers, 1969 (Box 129)
  - Seward, William. My friend Ernest Hemingway. London, A.S. Barnes and Co., 1969 (Box 129)
  - Sharp, Alan. A Green tree in Gedde. New York, New American Library, 1965 (Box 129)
  - Shipley, C.L. The Jade piccolo. New York, Atheneum, 1969 (Box 130)
  - Silone, Ignazio. Emergency exit. New York, Harper and Row, 1968 (Box 130)
  - Singer, Israel Joshua. The Family Carnovsky. New York, Vanguard Press, 1969 (Box 130)
  - Smith, Chard Powers. Where the light falls. New York, Macmillan, 1965 (Box 130)
  - Spencer, Elizabeth. Ship Island and other stories. New York, McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1968 (Box 130)
  - Steffens, Joseph Lincoln. The Letters of Lincoln Steffens, edited with introductory notes by Ella Winter and Granville Hicks. New York, Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1938; 3 folders (Box 131)
  - Swanberg, W.A. Dreiser. New York, Charles Scribner's Sons, 1965 (Box 131)
  - Van Dyke, Henry. Blood of strawberries. New York, Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1969 (Box 132)
  - Volponi, Paolo. My troubles began. New York, Grossman Publishers, 1964 (Box 132)
  - West, Anthony C. The Ferret fancier. New York, Simon and Schuster, 1965 (Box 132)
  - Five unidentified titles (Box 132)
  - Five unidentified titles (cont.) (Box 133)
- Manuscripts and published material about Granville Hicks
  - Harrington, Michael. "Granville Hicks' Small Town" from Taking Sides, 1985; originally from Dissent, 1957. (Box 124)
  - Levenson, Leah and Natterstad, Jerry. "Granville Hicks and the Small Town." Syracuse University Library Associates Courier, Fall 1985 (Box 124)
  - Robbins, Jack Alan. "Marxism and Literature in the 1930s" (Box 124)
  - Trathen, Marcia. "The Search for Certainty: America in the 1930's" (Box 124)
- Miscellaneous material
  - "Book Week." The Sunday Herald Tribune, Sept. 26, 1965 (Oversize 1)
  - The Communist, no. 10 (Oversize 1)
  - Contempo: a Review of Books and Personalities, vol. 1, no. 15, Jan. 1, 1932 (Oversize 1)
  - Die Fackel, Dec. 1917 (Oversize 1)
  - The Freeman, vol. 2, no. 34, Nov. 3, 1920 (Oversize 1)
  - The Hicks Library, undated; card catalog, 3 boxes (Oversize 3)
  - Metropolitan selections
    - Bernstein, Herman. "The Red Freedom", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John. "The Approach to War", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John and Robinson, Boardman. "At the Serbian Front", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John. "Back of Billy Sunday", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John. "The Battle", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John. "The Battle of La Cadena", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John. "Behind the Russian Retreat", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John. "The Colorado War", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John. "Francisco Villa -- the Man of Destiny", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John. "German France", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John. "In the German Trenches", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John. "Pinched in Poland", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John and Robinson, Boardman. "Serbia Between Battles", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John. "With La Tropa", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John. "With the Allies", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Reed, John. "With Villa on the March", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Rhodes, Harrison. "Sumurun: the Beautiful Play of Fatal Enchantment", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Shaw, Bernard. "The Case for Equality", Dec. 1913 (Oversize 1)
    - Shaw, George Bernard. "Shaking Hands With a Bear", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Shaw, George Bernard. "What the Films May Do to the Drama", undated (Oversize 1)
    - Drawing by Boardman Robinson [MISSING 23 May 2016], undated (Oversize 1)
    - Photographs of John Reed (3), Boardman Robinson, Fannie Hurst, Arthur Henry (Art) Young, Joyce Fair, Lydia Loupokowa (Oversize 1)
  - The Metropolitan Bulletin, May 1916? (Oversize 1)
  - The New York Communist, vol. 1, no. 1, Apr. 19, 1919 (Oversize 1)
  - The Partisan: Revolutionary Journal of Art, Literature and Opinion, vol. 1, no. 4, Mar. 1934
  - Die Russische Revolution in Bildern, no. 1, (St. Petersburg), Jan. 1918 (Oversize 1)
  - The Socialist, vol. 1, no. 1, Apr. 29, 1919 (Oversize 1)
  - The Socialist, vol. 1, no. 3, May 17, 1919 (Oversize 1)
  - La Verdadera Iberia, Sept. 20, 1910; lottery results (Oversize 1)
  - Der Völkerfriede, 1917 Dec-1918 Jan (Oversize 1)
  - Miscellaneous, Harvard Lampoon 40th anniversary celebration, 1916 (Oversize 1)
  - Miscellaneous, bullfighting, 2 items (Oversize 1)
  - Miscellaneous drawings, 4 items (Oversize 1)
  - Poster for exhibit "Art for The Masses (1911-1917): a Radical Magazine and its Graphics", 2 items (Oversize 2)